skribit.com 2009-06-22

# Privacy Policy: Skribit

_Last updated November 11, 2007_

Skribit understands how important the privacy of personal information is to its users. This Privacy Policy will tell you the minimal information that is collected through your use of this website. It will explain the choices you have about how your personal information is used and how we protect that information. It will also explain the security of the information we collect on your behalf when you register for a Skribit account. Skribit contains links to other sites. Once you enter another website, please be aware that Skribit is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. The only information we normally collect will be non-personal information through the use of cookies. Non-personal information is defined as data that is not traceable back to any individual and cannot be used to identify an individual, e.g. the keyword phrase you searched on to find this web site. However, if you choose to contact us, then you will be submitting personally identifiable information in the form of your name and email address along with anything else you volunteer. 

### NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

In general, you can browse Skribit without giving us any personal information. We use Skribit to analyze traffic to our web site in order to understand our customer and visitors needs and to continually improve our site for them. Skribit collects only anonymous, aggregate statistics. For example, we do not tie a specific visit to a specific visitor.

See the next section for more regarding the personal information that you voluntarily send to us.

### A. Cookies

What is a cookie? A cookie is a small data file that is stored on the hard drive of the computer you use to view a web site. 

Cookies placed by Skribit for users contain non-personally identifiable information. We collect non-personal information about your use of our web site and applications. Every computer that accesses Skribit is assigned a different cookie that allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using our services. We also may use cookie information to determine the popularity of certain content. Most web browsers such as Microsoft Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox, Opera, and Apple Safari can be set to reject all cookies and offer instructions on how to do so in the "Help" section of the toolbar. 

### VOLUNTEERING PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION

This Privacy Policy does not apply to content, business information, ideas, concepts or inventions that you send to Skribit by email, forum post, or blog comment. If you want to keep content or business information, ideas, concepts or inventions private or proprietary, do not send them in an email to us or post them to our forum.

A. Emails You Send to Skribit

When you contact Skribit, you are providing us with at minimum your email address. You may optionally provide us with additional information such as your real name or the company you represent. Skribit will keep this information in confidence and not share it with third parties. You will not be added to mailing lists unless requested. 

B. When you Comment on the Skribit Blog or application

C. Signing up for a Skribit Account

When you create a free Skribit account, you must provide us with a email address. This is the minimum information needed for us to provide the Skribit service. When you create an account, you can optionally provide us with additional information such as your real name, company, or title. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. We strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

Skribit processes personal information only for the purposes for which it was collected and in accordance with this Policy or any applicable service-specific privacy notice. We review our data collection, storage and processing practices to ensure that we only collect, store and process the personal information needed to provide or improve our services. We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we process is accurate, complete, and current, but we depend on our users to update or correct their personal information whenever necessary.

### SECURITY OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT ON YOUR BEHALF

At no time will the contents of your information collected on your behalf by subscribing for a Skribit account be shared with third parties. 

Skribit may provide aggregate quantitative data to third parties.

### SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us and information collected on your behalf, both during transmission and once we receive it. Please note that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

### DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION

By using Skribit, you acknowledge and agree that Skribit may access, preserve, and disclose your account information and any information associated with that account if required to do so by law or in a good faith belief that such access preservation or disclosure is reasonably necessary to: (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request, (b) protect property or defend or assert legal rights in special cases, such as in response to a physical threat to you or others, (b) enforce our Terms of Use Policy, including investigation of potential violations hereof, (c) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues (including, without limitation, the filtering of spam), (d) respond to user support requests, or (e) protect the rights, property or safety of Skribit, its users and the public. Skribit will not be responsible or liable for the exercise or non-exercise of its rights under the Terms of Service.

In the event that we are legally compelled to disclose this information to a third party, we will attempt to notify you unless doing so would violate the law or court order. 

In addition, we may disclose personal information as described below.

A. Disclosure to Network and Maintenance Contractors

People working on our behalf to maintain the web site may sometimes have limited access to your username, email address, and URL in the course of providing products or services to Skribit. These contractors include vendors and suppliers that provide us with technology, services, and/or content for the operation and maintenance of our web site. Unless you notify us otherwise, these contractors also may have access to any additional information you provided to us such as your real name, company, and title in the course of their testing. The only personally identifiable information accessible to these contractors is the minimum required to create an account (your username, email address, and URL). This is the minimum necessary for the contractor to perform their limited functions for Skribit. We also contractually require that our operations and maintenance contractors (1) protect the privacy of your email address consistent with this Privacy Policy, and (2) not use or disclose it for any purpose other than providing us with products and services as required by law. 

B. Disclosure of Aggregate Information

Skribit may provide general aggregate information to third parties. This sort of statistical data is called aggregate information because it reflects the habits and characteristics of a large group of anonymous people. Web Sites may use aggregate data or share it with their business partners so that the information and services they provide best meet the needs of the users.

We require parties with whom we share aggregate information to agree that they will not attempt to make this information personally identifiable in any way, such as by combining it with other databases.

### PROTECTION OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Despite Skribit's best efforts to protect your information while using our web site, there is always some risk that an unauthorized third party may find a way around our security systems or that transmissions of your information over the Internet may be intercepted.

Skribit processes personal information only for the purposes for which it was collected and in accordance with this Policy or any applicable service-specific privacy notice. We review our data collection, storage and processing practices to ensure that we only collect, store and process the personal information needed to provide or improve our services. We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we process is accurate, complete, and current, but we depend on our users to update or correct their personal information whenever necessary.

### PRIVACY OF CHILDREN

We are committed to protecting the privacy of children. Skribit is not designed for or intended to attract children under the age of 13. We do not collect personally identifiable information from any person we actually know is under the age of 13. Children's parents or guardians are solely responsible for providing supervision of any of their children's use of this web site. 

### CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

Skribit will keep the most up-to-date policy on this page accessible at http://www.skribit.com/privacy and will attempt to refer existing users to updates in the policy when they log into the web site. Any material changes in the way Skribit uses personal information will be described in future versions of this Privacy Policy, with the date of those changes clearly noted on the first page. We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Please exit the site immediately if you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy or any future revised policy.

### SERVICE-RELATED ANNOUNCEMENTS

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account by contacting service@skribit.com.

### CUSTOMER SERVICE

Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us when contacting us, or creating a Skribit service account, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request and to manage your account. We will communicate with you by email or telephone, in accordance with your wishes.
